Come on, it was this easy!
（ヤサコ）
天沢勇子(あまさわゆうこ)の言葉によると
According to Yuko Amasawa,
人と人とをつなぐ心の道は
細く途切れやすいそうです
the path of feelings that connects people
is thin and breaks easily.
（ヤサコ）ハァ…
（静江(しずえ)）ユウちゃん？
Yuko!
（静江）もう心配したんだから！
I was so worried!
私 どうしたの？
What happened to me?
そうだ 先生 呼ばなきゃ
Oh, right! I have to call the doctor!
先生！
あら 先生はどちらですか？
Doctor!
Oh my! Doctor, where are you?
あっ すみません… 先生！
Excuse me, doctor!
（オバちゃん）
メガネなら お母さんが持ってるわ
If you're looking for your glasses, your mother took them.
Aunty.
（ヤサコ）オバちゃん
（オバちゃん）あなたに似て
そそっかしい人ね
She's a bit spacey, just like you.
でも いい人だわ
But she's a good person.
Yuko Okonogi
よかったわ
Thank goodness.
あなたまで戻ってこなかったら
どうしようかと思った
I was so worried, thinking that you might not come back.
天沢さん…
Amasawa...
そうだ 私
天沢さんと学校に行って…
Right.
I went to school with Amasawa, and...
天沢さんは どうしたの？
What happened to Amasawa?
オバちゃん！
Aunty!
全てのリンクは切断されたわ
All the links have been disconnected.
And possibly,
多分 リンク先の空間も もう…
the Space those links went to as well...
has already...
（フミエ）よかった
本当によかった
Thank goodness!
Oh, thank goodness.
The kids cast
their glasses away
（フミエ）もうホントに
心配したのよ
I was really worried!
その… ああ…
Well, I...
あっちに
連れてかれたんじゃないかって
I thought you might've been taken to the other side.
（ヤサコ）あっち？
The other side?
（フミエ）みんな ウワサしてるわ
Everyone's talking about it.
イサコは連れて行かれたって
ミチコさんに
They say Isako was taken away.
By Miss Michiko.
Anyway, cheer up already!
ともかく 元気 出してね
あっ ちょっと…
京子(きょうこ)ちゃんの様子 見てくるから
Well, I'm gonna see how Kyoko is doing.
切るわね
I'm hanging up.
京子がどうかしたの？
What's wrong with Kyoko?
（フミエ）ヤサコ デンスケが…
Yasako,
Densuke is...
デンスケ？
Densuke?
（フミエ）
昨日の騒ぎで巻き込まれて
He was involved in yesterday's mess.
それで…
And so...
（フミエ）さっき メモリアルが
ヤサコのうちに届いたって
The memorial
has just arrived at your home.
また京子ちゃん騒いでる
Kyoko is kicking up a fuss again.
また電話するから
I'll call you back!
し… しっかりするのよ ヤサコ
You gotta hang in there, Yasako.
デンスケに会うの～！
Densuke's gone!
京子のメガネ どこ～？
Where are my glasses?!
（フミエ）
ああ… もう困ったな
ヤサコのお母さん―
Oh no... What a bother!
Yasako's mother confiscated Kyoko's glasses as well!
京子ちゃんのメガネまで
取り上げたのね
Densukeee...
Oh? Who could it be?
あら 誰かしら？
お母さん！
Mom?
（フミエの母）ここにいるって
小此木(おこのぎ)さんから聞いて
Mrs. Okonogi told me you were here.
あっ 返してよ！　何すんの？
G-Give them back!
What are you doing?!
（フミエの母）ダメです
もうメガネ遊びは許しません
No way.
I won't allow you to play with glasses anymore.
な… なんでよ！
But why?!
（フミエの母）
“なんで”じゃありません
There is no "why"!
聞いたわ！　クラスの子
メガネが原因で大ケガしたって
I know everything about your classmate.
I heard she was badly hurt because of the glasses.
（フミエの母）全部 知ってるのよ
I know everything.
天沢って子
夜中に学校に入り込んで
This Amasawa infiltrated the school at night,
and she fell down the stairs while using her glasses.
メガネで遊んでて
階段から落ちたんでしょ？
（フミエ）
ち… 違うの！　あれは…
It's all a lie.
That's because...
違いません！
ほら ご迷惑だから帰るわよ
It's not a lie!
Come on, stop disturbing other people and come back home.
But...
でも…
あんたも
ミチコさんに連れてかれるわよ
You'll be taken away by Miss Michiko too!
（ダイチ）か… 返してよ！
Give them back!
Idiot!
（ダイチの父）バッカもーん！
（ダイチ）ひぃ…
前から言っていただろ！
I already told you!
ずーっと
こんなものしているから―
If you always use these, you won't be able to distinguish reality from illusions anymore!
本物と偽物の区別が
つかなくなるんだ！
They say you can leave the hospital today.
（オバちゃん）
今日中には退院できるそうよ
単なる貧血とか そんなところね
It must have been a mild anemia or something like that.
The facts about yesterday's events won't be disclosed to the public.
昨日の出来事は―
表向きの社会では
何も知られずに終わる
私も事情を聞かれたけど―
I was also interrogated about it,
こんなのオカルト話にしかならない
but this will be left as a simple mystery story.
私が起こした
４年前の事件と同じように
Just like the accident I caused four years ago.
メガマスも それを読んで
私や猫目(ねこめ)を派遣したのね
Megamass also knows about this.
That's why they dispatched Nekome and me.
猫目は４年前
一緒にキラバグ集めをしてた男よ
Four years ago, Nekome was the guy who collected kirabugs with me.
今は もみ消す側だけどね
Although now he's helping with the cover-up.
Both kirabugs and Coil Space
キラバグもコイルスの空間も
もう どこにも残ってない
have completely disappeared.
And even if they're still around somewhere,
あるとしたら 都市伝説の
はざま交差点くらいかな
it must be at some place like the Loophole Nexus from urban legends.
There's no way to bring back Isako's consciousness...
イサコの意識を
呼び戻す方法は もう…
anymore.
It's as if...
（ヤサコ）なんだか…
It's as if I can't feel anything anymore.
なんだか なんにも感じないの
悪い夢かなんかだったみたい
何もかも
As if it was a bad dream,
or something like that.
Nothing but a dream.
Yasako...
ヤサコ
I see...
（ヤサコ）そっか
Densuke...
デンスケ メモリアル届いたのね
The memorial has arrived.
Your mother is almost done filling out the forms.
お母さん
手続き もうすぐ終わるわ
I'm off for a while too.
私 ちょっと外すわね
You should know that during yesterday's fuss, Mega-baa also went to the hospital.
実は メガばあも
昨日の騒ぎで緊急入院したの
Well, that's for her strained back.
ギックリ腰だけどね
Oh, my back...
（骨が鳴る音）
（メガばあ）うっ！　腰が…
I told you not to call me when I'm at work, didn't I, Takeru?
（猫目）仕事中は
電話するなと言っただろ タケル
But I'm...
（タケル）で… でも 僕
本当にこれでよかったのか…
I'm worried that what I did was wrong.
Don't worry.
（猫目）心配するな
Until now, did you ever make a mistake by doing what I said?
今まで兄ちゃんの言うとおりにして
間違ったことあるか？
Never, brother.
（タケル）ないよ 兄ちゃん
Also, about Kanna,
カンナのことも
僕が書いた話をみんな信じてる
everyone believes what I wrote.
Okay, take care of the Mystery Club.
（猫目）
ああ 怪奇クラブのほうは任せる
If it's for you,
（タケル）僕 兄ちゃんのためなら
なんでもする
I'd do anything.
Yes, I know.
（猫目）ああ 分かってる
Bye.
We've got nothing to do.
（ダイチ）やることがないな
You're right, Daichi.
（デンパ）そうだね　ダイチ
（アキラ）クラスのみんなも―
Everyone else in class got their glasses confiscated as well.
ほとんど親に
取り上げられちゃったみたいです
We can't even make a phone call.
これじゃ 電話もかけられないわ
Oh?
んっ？　なんだ お前らもか
You too?
Yup.
（ナメッチ）へい
Tsk...
チェッ メガネがないんじゃ
ケンカする気も起きないぜ
Without my glasses, I don't even feel like fighting.
Does it hurt somewhere?
（静江）痛いところない？
あなたも転んだんでしょ？
You fell as well, didn't you?
No, I'm all right.
（ヤサコ）うん 大丈夫
You know, Dad has gone to Kanazawa for work.
（静江）
お父さんね 今 出張で金沢(かなざわ)
He's never here when I need him.
大変なときに
必ずいないんだから
Your friend...
お友達 天沢さんだっけ？
Amasawa, right?
I hope she gets better soon.
早くよくなるといいわね
仲のいいお友達だったんでしょ？
You're good friends, right?
Isn't that so?
違うの？
Yuko...
ユウちゃん
We received a "memorial" from the pet company.
ペット会社から
メモリアルっていうのが来てるわ
Your glasses pet...
メガネのペット
デンスケちゃんだったわよね
Densuke was his name, right?
Really, I don't know anything about your friends, Yuko.
お母さん ユウちゃんの
お友達のこと なんにも知らなくって
Densuke...
デンスケちゃん 亡くなったそうね
is dead, you know.
（解説者）電脳局の者は
各省庁のドメインにも
The Cybermanagement staff can forcibly enter the domain of any ministry.
強制執行ができるのです
ただ 今回は特別で―
But they say this time is just an exception, ending at four this afternoon.
午後４時までという
期限付きだったようです
In this case,
としたら―
あれほど大規模に2.0を
繰り出すことはもうなさそうね
I don't think there will be another massive 2.0.
（猫目）
ああ 管理室でも大騒ぎだったぞ
Yeah, it put the Operations Center in turmoil.
猫目 来てたの？
Nekome? You were here?
The supervisor is out of town for work, so I'm taking his place for now.
室長が出張で
今 僕が室長代行だ
Listen, do you know which hospital room is Amasawa's?
ねえ 天沢勇子の病室
どこにあるか知ってる？
I'd like to meet her relatives,
彼女の家族に会いたいんだけど
病院が教えてくれないのよ
but the hospital won't tell me.
I don't know either.
（猫目）僕も知らないんだ
Megamass is in possession of her body, actually.
彼女の身柄は
メガマスが押さえている
Amasawa tried to open the same passage a year ago, but she failed.
天沢は１年前にも同じような通路を
開こうとして失敗している
Actually, she must be involved somehow in Kanna Ashihara's accident.
やはり 葦原(あしはら)カンナの一件にも
関係しているようだ
I'd like to think you're wrong.
（オバちゃん）
間違いだと思いたいわね
Don't throw away your hopes, Tamako.
希望を捨てるな 玉子(たまこ)
研一(けんいち)君のときだってなんとかなった
After all, Ken's case was also solved somehow.
I'm gonna look for some more clues.
まだ手がないか調べてみるさ
You're such a reliable man!
To think that you used to be my porter!
頼もしいね
昔は私のパシリだったくせに
Hey, I'm nothing more than the replacement room supervisor.
おいおい 今は室長代行だぞ
Then you too should do everything in your power to find the truth.
じゃ 君も個人の権限で
真相を探ってくれ
やってみるわ
Sure, I'll try.
ユウちゃん ちょっと座って
Yuko,
please sit down for a moment.
デンスケ かわいそうだったわね
Poor little Densuke.
私は あまりメガネを使わないから
よく分からないけど
I don't use glasses much, so I don't really know, but...
お母さんも昔 飼っていたのよ
You know, mama also used to have a pet.
１年くらいで死んじゃって
He died after about a year.
すごく泣いたわ 納得いかなくてさ
I cried so much.
I couldn't accept it.
“なんで ちっちゃい生き物って
すぐ死んじゃうんだろう？”って
Why a little creature...
dies so soon?
ペットって
大抵 人間より寿命が短いじゃない
Well, it's a fact that a pet's life is shorter than a person's.
“なんで そう決まってるの？”
Why is it like that?
“ペットが
人間より長生きだったら―”
If only pets lived longer than people,
“こんな思いをすることも
ないのに”って
I wouldn't have to be so sad...
そしたらね 金沢のおばあちゃんが
こう言ったの
And then,
my Granny from Kanazawa said,
“飼い主がペットの死ぬところを
見たくないように”
"The owner doesn't want to see his pet die,
“ペットだって飼い主が死ぬとこ
見たくないんじゃないか”って
and perhaps the pet too doesn't want to see its owner die?"
だから悲しみに耐えられる
人間のほうが―
That's why a human, who can resist sadness better,
ペットの代わりに
その悲しみを引き受けるのよ
feels that pain instead of a pet.
だって 人間のほうが
体 大きいもの
After all, a human's body is bigger.
本物のペットの話だけどね
But I'm talking about real pets.
ユウちゃん
Yuko...
（ヤサコ）お母さん？
Mom.
（静江）
お母さんの体 あったかい？
Is Mama's body warm?
Yeah.
（静江）柔らかい？
Soft?
Yeah.
（静江）ちょっと痛い？
Does it hurt a bit?
Yeah.
（静江）分かる？　ユウちゃん
Do you understand, Yuko?
こうして触れるものが…
The things you can touch, like this,
あったかいものが
信じられるものなの
the warm things,
are the things you can believe.
ギュッとやると
ちょっとくすぐったくて
Things that when you hug them feel a bit tickly, or hurt a bit.
ちょっと痛いの
分かる？
Got it?
（ヤサコ）お母さん
Mom...
Yuko.
ユウちゃん
それが生きてるってことなの
This is what it means to be alive.
メガネの世界はそれがないでしょ？
ユウちゃん
There's nothing like this
in the world of glasses, is there, Yuko?
戻ってきなさい 生きている世界に
Come back.
To the world of the living.
あったかい世界に
To a warm world.
お母さん
Mom...
So, be done with glasses now.
だから メガネは もうおしまい
代わりに 携帯 買ってあげる
I'll buy you a cell phone instead.
退屈したら一緒に遊んであげる
If you're bored, I'll play with you.
だから…
So...
だから もうメガネは
もうおしまい
So, be done with glasses now.
Yes.
（猫目）
はい 当面は こちらの病室です
From now on, this will be her hospital room.
改装はすぐ終わります
詳しくは下で…
The reorganization will end soon.
For an explanation, come here.
So he was lying, after all.
やはりウソか
４４２３？
昔 来たときはなかったのに…
4-4-2-3?
There wasn't a room like this when I was here last time!
（イサコの叔父）どちら様かな？
Who are you?
（オバちゃん）
これが私の知っている
今までの一部始終です
That's everything I know about the story.
I see...
そうですか
（オバちゃん）
あまり驚かないんですね
You don't seem surprised.
勇子さんは
兄を死なせたのは自分だと
Yuko believed that she was the one who made her brother die.
そう言っていたそうです
もしかして…
Maybe that's...
（叔父）はい
信彦(のぶひこ)は すでに他界しています
Yes, Nobuhiko has passed away.
You know, she's been very unfortunate.
この子は不憫(ふびん)な子で…
幼い頃に父親を亡くし
信彦だけが心の支えでした
She lost her father when she was little,
and the only one who could console her was her brother.
でも母親も病気で
入院することになって
In addition, her mother fell ill and needed time to recover.
２人をうちで
預かることになったんです
So my wife and I had to take care of Yuko and her brother.
ところが引っ越しの日に
勇子と信彦は交通事故に遭って
But the day they moved,
Yuko and Nobuhiko were involved in a car accident,
２人とも意識不明に…
and they both were knocked unconscious.
Both of them?
２人とも？
（叔父）はい
Yes.
（叔父）そのとき 勇子を治療したのが
小此木先生でした
The one who healed Yuko was Dr. Okonogi.
（オバちゃん）
イマーゴの電脳医療だわ
That must've been the Imago cybercure.
（叔父）それがどんなものなのか
私にはさっぱり分かりませんが
I haven't the slightest idea
what it was,
勇子だけは目覚めました
その間の記憶を全て失って…
but only Yuko regained consciousness.
She lost her memory of that time.
小此木先生が亡くなった頃だわ
That's also the time when Dr. Okonogi passed away.
信彦君は
そのとき どうなったんです？
Then what happened to Nobuhiko?
Well...
それはメガマスの契約があって
言えないのです
Because of my contract with Megamass, I can't tell you.
（オバちゃん）
お願いします どうしても…
I beg you! No matter what it costs!
（叔父）２２です
Twenty two.
（オバちゃん）えっ？
（叔父）今は これだけしか…
That's all I can say for now.
（イサコの叔母）
ちょっと あなた！
Hey, honey!
You're from Cybermanagement, aren't you?
あなた 空間管理室の人でしょ？
二度と近よらないでください
Don't come here anymore!
待って！
２２って どういう意味ですか？
Wait!
What does 22 mean?
（フミエ）ヤサコ！
Yasako!
元気 出しなよ
Snap out of it!
ああ…
私もメガネ取り上げられちゃった
My glasses have been confiscated too.
（ヤサコ）なんでだろう？
I wonder why.
涙が出ないの
The tears won't come.
ヤサコ？
Yasako...
（ヤサコ）なんか…
Somehow...
まだデンスケが死んだって
ピンと来なくて
I still can't believe that Densuke's dead.
それに天沢さんのことも…
And...
Also about Amasawa.
私って薄情者(もん)なのかな？
Maybe I'm heartless?
フミエちゃんの言うとおりだ
感情移入したら損だね
It's like you said.
If you get too attached, you'll get hurt.
ヤサコ
Yasako...
（ヤサコ）
でもバカみたい この辺が痛いの
But I feel so stupid.
It hurts here.
まるで デンスケが
本物の犬だったみたい
As if Densuke was a real dog.
私や京子を元気づけようと
いつも一生懸命だった
He always did everything he could
to cheer up Kyoko and me.
さよならも言えなかった
I couldn't even say goodbye.
デンスケの毛並みに触りたいって
いつも思ってた
I always wanted to stroke his fur.
When I was little,
小さい頃 デンスケに触っても
感触がないことが分からなくて
I couldn't understand why I didn't feel Densuke's fur when I touched him.
そのうち
触れるようになるんじゃないかって
So I believed that one day I would be able to feel it.
分かってた
デンスケは本物の生き物じゃない
I knew it.
I knew that Densuke wasn't real.
だから 死ぬときも
痛くなかったと思う
So...
I think he didn't feel pain when he died.
ヤサコ
Yasako...
だから 私も痛くない
データが消えただけ
So I don't feel pain anymore either.
It's only data that has disappeared.
それだけ　だから…
Only that.
That's why...
（ヤサコ）ハッ…
（フミエ）どうしたの？
What's wrong?
デンスケ…
（フミエ）ヤサコ？
Densuke?
Yasako?
一体どうしたの？
What on earth is wrong with you?
聞こえたの
（フミエ）何が？
I heard it!
What?
デンスケの声がしたの 一瞬だけど
I heard Densuke's voice!
Only for an instant...
I'm not lying! I'm sure he's here!
ウソじゃない！
絶対いる この辺りに
（犬のほえ声）
（ヤサコ）デンスケ！
Densuke!
死んでしまった…
He's dead...
He's really dead... really.
ホントに死んでしまったのね…
デンスケ…
Densuke...
記録にあるコイルドメインは
全て消滅か
So, every Coil Domain in the records has vanished.
残る手がかりは
せいぜい都市伝説くらいね
The only possible clue, now, is the urban legends...
んっ？　これは…
What's this?
Hello.
Wait!
待って！　私の話を聞いてください
Please listen to me!
甥(おい)が解析したカンナのメガネに
ある情報が含まれてて…
In Kanna's glasses, there was some information that my nephew parsed!
（ヤサコ）
なんだか 全部 夢だったみたい
I feel like...
everything was just a dream.
（京子）フサフサだったよ
He was so fluffy.
いい匂いがしたよ
He smelled so good.
あったかかったよ
He was so warm...
もう だから… ユウちゃんに
ケガはなかったんだって
I told you! Yuko wasn't hurt.
何度 言ったら分かるのよ
How many times do I have to tell you?
うん 今 代わるわね
I'll put you through to her.
ユウちゃん お父さんよ
Yuko, it's Daddy.
フッ まだ子供なのね
She's still a child, after all.
あっ そっか… もういないんだ
Right, they're not here anymore.
メガネも デンスケも
Neither my glasses,
nor Densuke.
I wonder what this is?
なんだろう？　これ
My heart hurts.
胸が痛い
"All the things you see with glasses are nothing but fakery."
（イサコ）
メガネで見えるものなんて
全てまやかしだ
"Believe only in things you can touch with your hands."
手で触れられるものだけを
信じるんだ
Amasawa thinks the same thing.
（ヤサコ）
天沢さんも同じこと言ってる
This world is really made only of things people can touch with their hands.
この世界は皆
手で触れるものでできている
When you touch something,
手で触るとサラサラだったり
フカフカだったり
it can feel silky... or fluffy...
From now on,
これからは手で触れるものだけを
信じて生きていこう
I want to live by believing only in what I can touch with my hands.
手で触れられないものは まやかし
Things I can't touch are nothing but illusions.
So these sad feelings must be illusions too.
だから この悲しい気持ちも
きっとまやかし
Actually, I'm not sad at all.
ホントは悲しくなんかない
These painful feelings will vanish in no time.
こんなツラい気持ちも
きっとすぐに忘れる
After all,
だって まやかしなんだもの…
they're just illusions.
本当に？
In reality...
本物って何？
What is "real"?
手で触れられるものが本物なの？
Are things I can touch real?
手で触れられないものは
本物じゃないの？
So, things I can't touch
aren't real?
今 本当に
ここにあるものは何？
What things are actually here?
間違いなく
今 ここにあるものって何？
The things that are here without any doubt...
What are they?
The pain in my heart.
胸の痛み
The thing that's really here, at this moment,
今 本当に ここにあるものは
この胸の痛み
is the pain in my heart!
It's not an illusion.
これは まやかしなんかじゃない
I can't touch it with my hands,
手で触れられないけど
but all I can feel right now
今 信じられるのは この痛みだけ
is this pain.
この痛みを感じる方向に
本当の何かがある
Where the pain is coming from,
there is something real.
ユウちゃん…
Yuko!
To mom
Sorry, I'm not going to school today.
I'm going to Kanazawa.
Please don't worry, Yuko
ケ… ケンちゃん
Sorry. I borrowed your glasses.
Ken!
（タケル）兄ちゃん
本当に僕らがしていることは
Brother...
Is what we're doing really going to help clear our father's name?
父ちゃんの
名誉のためになるんだろうか？
（猫目）また その話か
That again?
（タケル）でも悪くない人まで
巻き込んだりして
But involving people who have nothing to do with it...
そんなの…
It's so...
Are you talking about Kanna Ashihara?
葦原カンナのことか？
あれは
はっきり事故だったじゃないか
You know that was clearly an accident.
４４２３のハンドルで
２回も警告したのに
But I used the 4423 handle to provide a warning twice.
Of all things,
よりにもよって―
通路を開いている最中に
のこのこやってくるなんて…
how could I ever expect that right in the middle of opening the passage,
誰が予想できる？
someone would come out of nowhere...
And as if that wasn't enough, she had the Imago too.
それも
イマーゴを持っていたなんて…
分離を起こした電脳体をよけて
The Cybernavi dodged Kanna's shifted cyberbody, but crushed her flesh-and-blood body.
電脳ナビは
生身のほうをはねてしまった
痛ましいことだが 我々には
どうしようもなかったんだ
As heartbreaking as that was, we couldn't do anything about it.
But we also lost a rare opportunity and our kirabugs.
こっちこそめったにないチャンスと
キラバグを失った
そのために
どれだけ苦労したことか
Remember what terrible hardships we went through?
さあ メシを食え
Come on, eat.
学校には
病欠の手続きをとっておいたから
I justified your absence from school today as illness.
I heard that both of them are missing!
（一小の生徒１）
２人ともって話だぜ
（一小の生徒３）
それって もしかして…
Maybe it's...
（３人）駆け落ち～？　アハハハッ
a love tryst?
（フミエ）やめなさいよ！
（一小の生徒１）んだと？
Stop it already!
What?
（一小の生徒３）てめえ
メガネなきゃ何もできないくせに！
You worm! You're powerless without your glasses!
や… やめてあげて！
Please stop!
あっ？　うっさいよ！
Shut up!
（アイコ）やめなさいよ！
（一小の生徒１）すっこんでろ！
Stop it already!
Don't interfere!
Stop! Stop!
キャーキャー うるさ…
（フミエ）やめて イヤ！
Shut up, I say!
No!
One, two...
せーの！
だあっ…
Good.
よし！　やっぱり腰だ
なんだよ 簡単じゃん
So it's all about the hips, after all.
ダイチ！
Daichi?!
何しやがんだ… こんにゃろう！
Hey, you damn bastard! What the hell are you doing?
（ダイチ）ワッショイ！
やっぱり腰で回す
So it really is all in the hips.
すごいよ ダイチ
You're awesome, Daichi!
何度も投げられると
強くなるってホントだな
It's actually true that the more you're thrown, the stronger you become!
おい お前ら！
Hey, you!
二度と こっちの生徒に
手を出すな！
Don't lay your hands on the kids here anymore!
（３人）へ～い…
Yah...
オ… オヤビン
Boss!
なんの用かね？　ナメッチ君
What do you want, Namecchi?
チャック開いてます
（ダイチ）んがっ…
Your zipper is open.
Login successful
よかった ログインできる
All right, I can login.
To: Yuko Okonogi - The other party is not available.
やはり つながらないな
After all, I can't connect to her...
Mayumi of Kanazawa
What the hell are the two of you thinking?
（オバちゃん）２人とも
一体 どうするつもりよ！
Login successful
（ヤサコ）よかった まだ動くわ
Great! It's still working.
重いな メール メール…
She's not around...
Mail, mail...
あった
Here!
これだわ
It's this one!
このマンホール…
These manholes...
やっぱり あのとき
マユミが言ってた場所が…
As I thought...
The place Mayumi was talking about back then is...
はざま交差点なんだわ
the Loophole Nexus!
（ヤサコ）マユミ
そんなに簡単には会えないよね？
Mayumi, we can't face each other easily.
Answering machine service
あのときのこと
いろんなことがあったから
Back then, many things happened.
ひと言では言えないけど
I can't say it in few words, but...
私 会いたいの
But I want to meet you.
あのとき マユミの言ってた場所
The place you were talking about...
４つのマンホールが並んでる―
the place with the four manholes...
あの場所は本当にあったのよ
古い空間の中に
it really exists.
In the obsolete Space.
でも それだけじゃない
But not only that.
Mayumi,
マユミ あなたが私を
いじめてたなんてもう思ってない
I don't think anymore that you were bullying me.
あなたは
ミチコさんが怖かっただけで
You were only afraid of Miss Michiko, because you'd never...
決して…
（マユミ）私がいじめてた？
（ヤサコ）あっ…
I bullied you?
いじめていたのは
あなたのほうじゃない
You were the one who bullied me.
Preview
Next time on Dennou Coil:
Kanazawa City, Loophole Nexus
Kanazawa City
Loophole Nexus
See you next time.
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
〝金沢市
はざま交差点 〞
お楽しみに